<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on </title>
    <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 13:33:30 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.geofftuttle.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Antares Launch</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/antares-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 13:33:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/antares-launch/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, I got a chance to see the Antares rocket take off from Wallops Flight Facility. The facility is on the Atlantic coast of Maryland, and I am roughly 50 miles away on the west side of the Chesapeake. The mission was a resupply to the International Space Station, carrying cheese, nitrogen, and other essential items.
Camera Setup My wife and I got out there early enough to get my camera setup, a simple tripod holding a Canon T3i with a 55-250mm zoom lens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Scaling With Python</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/hugo-image-scaling-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:55:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/hugo-image-scaling-with-python/</guid>
      <description>This blog is built using Hugo, a static website generator designed for quick build times and easy deployment. A static website requires no server backend, since everything is delivered in a static state to the reader (that&amp;rsquo;s you!). All code is executed on the client machine. I love the lightweight simplicity of a static website, which brings up some nostalgia for the internet of the mid to late 90s, when these types of pages were the norm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goin&#39; Walkabout and DSLRs</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/week-in-review-003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 22:19:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/week-in-review-003/</guid>
      <description>This past week has been a bit slow. I have been preoccupied with a lot of work-related things, and was not in much of a mood to work on the usual hobbies of painting/printing/casting. While I may not have created too much, I spent a lot of time this week taking walks in the neighborhood. I suppose I could say this created a clear headspace from which to move into the next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Painting Minis and More Casting</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/week-in-review-002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 17:08:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/week-in-review-002/</guid>
      <description>This has been a week with a lot of painting, a little casting, and a bit of thinking about future projects.
Painting Finished Tank Early in the week, I was able to wrap up my Schrek tank build, which gave me a chance to get some experience in basing. The base seen above was the third iteration, where I finally got the spacing between the dirt piles right. This allowed the tank sat on the base instead of floating above the rocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnets, Casting, and Real Hobby Paint</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/week-in-review-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 06:21:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/week-in-review-001/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a pretty productive week, and I got a chance to try out a bunch of new things and get some ideas for future projects a bit outside my norm. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to this week:
Magnets, Painting with Vallejo, and Basing To make my growing Battletech collection a bit more modular (and to keep from making/buying too many minis) I have been toying with the idea of swappable turrets and weapons for my pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Part Mold Making</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/two-part-mold-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/two-part-mold-making/</guid>
      <description>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to take a 3d printed tabletop miniature and replicate it with a two part mold. This will speed of production of a part that would normally take two to three hours, and give us the freedom of different materials and colors.
Two part molds allow us to cast more complex shapes than a one part, or open-face, mold. This open face creates a flat surface on the piece we are making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RC Plane From Pen Plotter</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/projects/rc-planes/rc-plane-from-pen-plotter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 16:38:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/projects/rc-planes/rc-plane-from-pen-plotter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a bit of mulling over the last RC plane adventure, I decided to jump back in with another build. I wanted something that looked sharp, was somewhat compact, and dedicated to training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flitetest.com/articles/flite-test-tiny-trainer&#34;&gt;FT Tiny Trainer&lt;/a&gt;, a scratch-build design from Flite Test.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foam Plane</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/projects/rc-planes/foam-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 16:38:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/projects/rc-planes/foam-plane/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I was a kid, I have had an interest in remote controlled anything. When I was younger, I had a few RC cars, like a Rebound that could drive even when flipped over, and another dune buggy style that was less forgiving when upside down.
However, anything that flew was prohibitively expensive and probably would not have survived my &amp;ldquo;full throttle&amp;rdquo; approach to RC vehicles.
Fortunately, the rise of hobbyist electronics, DIY drones, and cheap components with cheap shipping from China has made RC planes a lot easier to get into, and a lot easier to rebuild after the inevitable crash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosplay Blaster</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/cosplay-blaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 15:48:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/cosplay-blaster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine recently joined the 501st, a group of Star Wars fans who cosplay in full sets of screen-accurate Stormtrooper armor for charity events. He opted for a biker scout variant, which includes a distinct laser pistol as a sidearm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help complete his set of armor, I printed a replica of this blaster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Home Mini Wall Mount</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/google-home-mini-wall-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 12:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/google-home-mini-wall-mount/</guid>
      <description>Over Christmas, I took advantage of Google&amp;rsquo;s sale on the Google Home Mini to pick up a few for the apartment. Even though it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take up a lot of desk space, I wanted to mount it to the wall to keep it off the limited shelf space, and to hear it throughout the room. To resolve this, I came up with the following wall mount. The design started with a few reference images I found online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch-Converting Video Files with Handbrake and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/batch-converting-video-files-with-handbrake-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 19:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/batch-converting-video-files-with-handbrake-and-python/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few years, I have acquired quite a video collection. Hundreds of files have been downloaded or DVDs ripped, resulting in nearly a terabyte of television and movies. I usually use Handbrake to rip files off a DVD, since it has several parameters that can be tweaked to give the ideal video output. I can easily name the file, specify an output format, and even create a queue for getting multiple videos from a disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikea Lamp to Camera Mount</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/ikea-lamp-to-camera-mount/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 02:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/ikea-lamp-to-camera-mount/</guid>
      <description>At less than $10, the Tertial lamp from Ikea is my favorite source of workspace illumination. So far, I have one in the garage over my workbench, and one over the desk in my office. They are easy to move into place, and will hold fast when let go. For the price, this lamp can&amp;rsquo;t be beat. The mechanics of these lamps is also interesting. Forces and torques are balanced through the weight of the lamp and counter-acting springs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printrbot Simple Metal Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/printrbot-simple-metal-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 12:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/printrbot-simple-metal-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Though I received it weeks ago, I finally got a chance to install the x-axis upgrade for my Printrbot. I now have 4 more inches in the x direction, and a heated build plate.
I also installed a new Ubis13 hotend to replace the offbrand E3DV6 that leaked all over the place. This required printing a new fan mount, which you can see coming off the hotend in the picture. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to printing with new materials and making use of the extra space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviving an Old Powderbed Printer</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/reviving-an-old-powderbed-printer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 10:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/reviving-an-old-powderbed-printer/</guid>
      <description>A little over a year ago, our group acquired this old ZCorp 310 printer from surplus. This machine uses powderbed technology, where an inkjet deposits liquid binder on a plaster material, fusing it together into a solid object. This brand of printer is rarely seen nowadays, since the company is now owned by 3D Systems. With no material, no accessories, and no software, we were unsure if it was even functional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filament Extrusion</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/filament-extrusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 03:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/filament-extrusion/</guid>
      <description>Despite the wide range of available thermoplastics, sometimes spools of filament with desirable electromagnetic or mechanical properties are not commercially available. For this reason, our research group acquired a Filabot filament extruder. Pellets of thermoplastic are loaded in through the hopper, and pushed through a heating element via an auger. The nozzles are bolts with different sized holes for 3 mm and 1.75 mm filament.
Today I got a chance to make some filament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CT Scan to STL</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/ct-scan-to-stl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 12:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/ct-scan-to-stl/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I have been reading on 3d printing in the medical field. The ability to go beyond a screen allows for visualization and practice of surgery without the patient having to go under the knife. A friend was kind enough to get me a copy of her recent CT scan data so I could attempt to get a 3d-printable object out of it. Using the guide found here, I had little trouble extracting the data, generating a model, and exporting it to an STL file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Nozzle Under The Microscope</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/new-nozzle-under-the-microscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 10:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/new-nozzle-under-the-microscope/</guid>
      <description>I picked up a new hot end for the Printrbot the other day. This one is modeled after the popular E3D V6 hot end, which has an all-metal design. Unfortunatly, you get what you pay for, and this inexpensive clone oozed out the top and bottom of the heater block. Lesson learned, buy the official tried-and-true equipment. While I was heating things up to remove the stray PLA, I was able to use one of the microscopes in the lab to check out the new 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Cell Print</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/silicon-cell-print/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 13:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/silicon-cell-print/</guid>
      <description>For a demonstration piece, I was sent a model of a silicon unit cell to print. This was an enjoyable endeavor, and lead to an interesting discovery in the post-processing procedure on the Form1+
I ended up printing two of these. One was left in the alcohol bath for 2 days, and when removed, was extremely flexible. While I need to be careful with the timing, the flex should make it more resistant to cracking, especially if the unit cell is being passed around during a demonstration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logo Print</title>
      <link>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/logo-print/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 15:49:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.geofftuttle.com/blog/logo-print/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day, I was tasked with 3d printing a logo from a nearby company. The design was a simple compass with a superimposed letter &amp;ldquo;e.&amp;rdquo; Being such a simple design, I decided to model it directly in AutoDesk Inventor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
